# **PUTHIMON "Patty" RUCKPOUNG**

Boston, MA | 617-602-3488 | puthimon.r@gmail.com | Linkedin.com/in/p-ruckpoung/

## SUMMARY

A recent graduate with M.S. in Business Analytics and an experienced Data Analyst with 8 months internship working at Math Magazine. Detail-oriented approach and system-based thinker that efficiently compiles and organizes data to optimize workflow and reporting needs.

Critical Thinking

**Problem Solving** 

Excel ETL

Storytelling

## **SKILLS**

- Business Intelligence (BI)
- **Data Analysis**
- **Data Visualization**
- Machine Learning

- **Database Development**
- Programming Languages including Python, SQL, and SAS
- Business Intelligence including Tableau, and Power BI

### PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

## MATH MAGAZINE, Brooklyn NY

Data Analyst Intern (May 2021 – Dec 2021)

May 2021 - Dec 2021

- Provided a depth market analysis, resulting in a 15.5% increase in sales and subscriptions.
- Conducted research using focus top 5 popular topics and increased site visit by 11.6% due to the finding.
- Used Google Analytics to track data, Excel to analyze data, and Power BI and Tableau to perform visualizations.

#### SUFFOLK UNIVERSITY. Boston MA

Jan 2021 - Dec 2021

Tutor in Business Analytics classes (Jan 2021 – Dec 2021)

- Held one-on-one appointments with students helping them with SQL, Python, Excel, Tableau, and SAS.
- Led a weekly group discussion to help students with the Data Management and Modeling class.
- Kept track of updated materials through active communication with faculty.

#### PROJECT EXPERIENCE

## SPOT EASY, Boston MA

Data Analytics Project (Jun 2021 – July 2021)

- Used analytics tools such as Google Analytics to track user retention on the traffic and trends.
- Analyzed site traffic, interpreted relationships, interpreted trends and patterns in complex datasets.
- Reported visualizations of business insights and relationships of prices and real estate conditions.

#### **EDUCATION**

## **SUFFOLK UNIVERSITY**

Boston MA

Master of Business Analytics GPA: 3.97

2021

- INTO Suffolk Progression Scholarship
- Relevant Courses: Data Management and Modeling (SQL), Python for Business Analytics, Business Intelligence and Data Analytics (Tableau and Power BI)

**KASETSART UNIVERSITY** (graduated with honors)

KamphaengSean Thailand

Bachelor of Arts and Sciences Major in English